Film Still Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Film Still Photograph Collection
1950-1990
VRC 66
Yale University Arts Library
4.16
10 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white photographs of European and American film stills, the majority from the early 20th century. Some material may overlap with or duplicate items in the VRC 35 mm slide collection. The majority of the material acquired from the Museum of Modern Art as part of their circulating film program. Accompanied by a small collection of brochures, catalogs, other publications, and a set of film strip negatives from the Museum of Modern Art, New York.
Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.)
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white photographs of European and American film stills, the majority from the early 20th century. Some material may overlap with or duplicate items in the VRC 35 mm slide collection. The majority of the material acquired from the Museum of Modern Art as part of their circulating film program. Accompanied by a small collection of brochures, catalogs, other publications, and a set of film strip negatives from the Museum of Modern Art, New York.
Arrangement
Arranged in two parts: a miscellaneous collection, alphabetically by nationality; and the Museum of Modern Art film still series, arranged by alphabetically by nationality and by CGB catalog numbers.
Motion pictures -- History -- 20th Century; Film stills; Reproductions; Photographs
- Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  General
  [5 photographs]
  Includes a folder of clippings
- General works (Box 1)
  - Britain [2 photographs] (Box 1)
  - Denmark [1 photograph] (Box 1)
  - France [ 63 photographs] (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous works [42 photographs] (Box 1)
    - The passion of Joan of Ark [21 photographs] (Box 1)
- Germany (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous works [25 photographs] (Box 2)
  - The cabinet of Dr. Caligari [22 photographs] (Box 2)
  - The Golem [7 photographs] (Box 2)
  - Siegfried [5 photographs] (Box 2)
- Russia (Box 2)
  [2 photographs]
- United States (Box 2)
  [16 photographs]
- Museum of Modern Art Filmstrip Collection (Box 3)
  - Kinematography (CGB 222) [43 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Production. (CGB 225) [44 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Early American and European. (CGB 137) ][6 photographs] (Box 3)
  - Britain. 112 photographs (Box 4)
    - Feature film, part 1 (CGB 226) [33 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Feature film, part 2 (CGB 227) [40 photographs] (Box 4)
    - Sound (CGB 228) [39 photographs] (Box 4)
  - France [73 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Silent (CGB 151) [35 photographs] (Box 5)
    - Sound (CGB 152) [38 photographs] (Box 5)
  - Germany [72 photographs] (Box 6)
    - Sound (CGB 123) [36 photographs] (Box 6)
  - Russia [65 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Silent (CGB 86) [31 photographs] (Box 7)
    - Sound (CGB 87) [34 photographs] (Box 7)
  - United States [132 photographs] (Box 8)
    - Silent (CGB 253) [41 photographs] (Box 8)
    - Sound, part 1 (CGB 254) [ 47 photographs] (Box 8)
    - Sound, part 2 (CGB 255) [44 photographs] (Box 9)
- Museum of Modern Art (Box 10)
  [Circulating Film Library brochures, catalogs, and negative strips.]
  - Negative strips. 48 strips (Box 10)
  - 711M. [8 strips] (Box 10)
  - 712M. [8 strips] (Box 10)
  - 717M. [6 strips] (Box 10)
  - 719M. [7 strips] (Box 10)
  - 720M. [7 strips] (Box 10)
  - 721M. [5 strips] (Box 10)
  - 722M. [7 strips] (Box 10)
- Circulating film programs. 4 catalogs (Box 10)
  - [undated], 1947, 1952, 1955 (Box 10)
- The film till now 1895-1946 (Box 10)
  - 1950 [1 brochure] (Box 10)
- Documentary and experimental films (Box 10)
  [2 catalogs]
  - 1948, 1953 (Box 10)
- Recent Film Library acquisitions (Box 10)
  [3 brochures]
  - 1956-1959 (Box 10)
  - Typescript supplement, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Supplement, 1959. (Box 10)
- Film Library report, 1941-1956 (Box 10)
  [1 pamphlet]
  [Various price lists and advertisements.] 21 pamphlets and fliers. (most from the 1990s) Film notes, part I: The silent film: The Bulletin of the Museum of Modern Art 16 (2-3), 1949. 1 issue.